<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles to be enquired of, within the archdeaconry of Glocester, in the ge[ne]rall visitation of the right wor. M. Samuel Burton, Archdeacon of the dioces of Glocester holden in the yeere of our Lord God, 1618, in the 16. yeere of the raigne of our most gracious soueraigne Lord James, by the grace of God, King of Great Britaine, France &amp; Ireland, defender of the faith, &amp;c.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Diocese of Gloucester.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1618</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 38 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00183</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10213.3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S4279</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">24047958</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 24047958</idno>
            <idno type="VID">27114</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00183)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 27114)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1815:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles to be enquired of, within the archdeaconry of Glocester, in the ge[ne]rall visitation of the right wor. M. Samuel Burton, Archdeacon of the dioces of Glocester holden in the yeere of our Lord God, 1618, in the 16. yeere of the raigne of our most gracious soueraigne Lord James, by the grace of God, King of Great Britaine, France &amp; Ireland, defender of the faith, &amp;c.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Diocese of Gloucester.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[15] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Nathaniel Butter,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1618.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴.</note>
                  <note>Title in ornamental border.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Lincoln College Library (University of Oxford).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Government.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:27114:1"/>
            <p>ARTICLES TO BE ENQVIRED OF, WITHIN THE ARCH<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deaconty of Gloceſter, in the <hi>ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Viſitation of the Right</hi> Wor: M. <hi>Samuel Burton, Archdeacon of the Dio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Gloceſter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Holden in the yeere of our Lord <hi>God,</hi> 1618. <hi>In the</hi> 16. <hi>yeere of the</hi> Raigne or our moſt gracious So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ueraigne Lord <hi>James,</hi> by the grace <hi>of God, King of Great Britaine, France &amp; Ireland, Defender of the Faith, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for <hi>Nathaniel Butter.</hi> 1618.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath">
            <pb facs="tcp:27114:2"/>
            <head>The tenor of the Oath to be miniſtred to the <hi>Church-wardens and Sworne-men.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>YOu ſhall Sweare, that vpon due conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of the Articles giuen you in charge to preſent vnto; You ſhall particularly preſent all the Wants &amp; De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fects; and alſo all offences and offenders therin required of: wherein you ſhall deale truly and faithfully: So help you God.</p>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <bibl>
                     <hi>LEVIT. 19.12.</hi>
                  </bibl>
                  <p>Yee ſhall not ſweare by my Name falſely; neither ſhalt thou profane the Name of thy God.</p>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:27114:2"/>
            <head>ARTICLES TO BEE <hi>ENQVIRED OF WITHIN THE</hi> Archdeaconrie of the Dioceſſe of Gloceſter, in the Viſitation to be holden in the yeere of our <hi>Lord God,</hi> 1618.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <head>¶ Articles concerning the Cleargie.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hether hath your Miniſter read the Conſtitutions ſet foorth by his Maieſtie, once euery yéere, vpon ſome Sundaies or Holidaies, in the afternoone, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore diuine ſeruice; according as by the Canons he is bound?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doth your Miniſter vſe to pray for the Kings Maieſty, King <hi>Iames,</hi> &amp; for the Quéenes Maieſtie, the Prince, and all their royall Progenie, giuing vnto him ſuch ſtile and title of Supreme Gouernour, in all cauſes, and ouer all perſons, as well Eccleſiaſticall Temporall, as by law are due vnto him, exhorting their Pariſhioners to yéeld him obedience, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the ſame: and alſo in their ſayd Sermons, doe pray for all Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biſhops, Biſhops, and other Eccleſiaſticall perſons, according to the fifty fiue Canon?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether is the preſcript forme of diuine Seruice vſed by your mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter vpon Sundayes, Holidayes, Wedneſdaies, and Fridaies, according to the Booke of Common Prayer? And whether doth your miniſter duely obſerue all the orders, rites and ceremonies preſcribed in the ſaid booke of common prayer, as well in reading publike prayers, the Letany, as alſo in adminiſtring y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Sacraments in ſuch ma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ner &amp; forme wearing the Surples, as in the Booke of common prayer by law now eſtabliſhed, is enioyned.</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether doth your Miniſter adminiſter the holy Communion ſo often, and at ſuch time, as that euery Pariſhioner may receiue the ſame at the leaſt thrice in euerie yéere: whereof once at Eaſter, as by the booke of Common Praier is appointed? And whether doth your Miniſter re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiue the ſame himſelfe on euerie daie that hee adminiſtreth it to others, knéeling at the ſame, &amp; adminiſtreth it to none but ſuch as do knéele at the receiuing thereof, and vſe the words of the Inſtitution according to that booke at euerie time that the bread and wine is receiued, in ſuch manner &amp; forme as by the promiſe of the 21. Canon is directed, or wherein is hee faultie, and whether is warning giuen by him before hand for the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, as the 22. Canon requireth?</p>
               <p n="5">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27114:3"/>5 Whether hath your miniſter admitted any notorious Offenders, or Schiſmatiques to the Communion, contrary to the 26 and 27 conſtituti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, without ſatisfaction, by due courſe of Law before enioyned them; or reiected any from the Communion, who were not by publike preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or other open ſcandall infamous and detected of ſome notorious crime, by common fame publiſhed in the Pariſh?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether the Miniſter, together with the Church-wardens and Queſt-men, doe take diligent héede and care, that not onely all, and euery of your Pariſhioners doe receiue thrice in euery yéere, as aforeſaid: but alſo that no ſtrangers of any other Pariſh doe forſake their owne Miniſter and pariſh to receiue with you, contrary to the 28 Canon?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether doth your Miniſter vſe to ſigne the children with the ſigne of the croſſe when they are baptized, according to the Booke of Common Praier, and the thirtieth canon? and whether he hath deferred, or wilfully refuſed to baptize any infant in his pariſh being in danger, hauing béene duly enformed of the weakneſſe thereof: and whether the childe hath died in his default without baptiſme, contrary to the 68 and 69 canons?</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether is your miniſter continually reſident with you vpon his Benefice, or for how long time hath he been abſent: and where is he reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent for the moſt part, and what other Benefice hath he.</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether doth your miniſter, being a Preacher, preach vſually, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the conſtitutions, either in his owne cure with you, or elſe in ſome other church or chappell néere adioyning, where no Preacher is: ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the 45 Canon: or how oft hath he been negligent in that behalfe.</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether is your miniſter a Preacher allowed: if yea, then by whom: if not, whether doth hee procure Sermons to bee preached among you once in euery moneth at the leaſt, by ſuch as are lawfully licenſed, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the 46 canon, or doth contribute toward a licenced Preacher, if his liuing will beare it?</p>
               <p n="11">11 Whether hath your miniſter another Benefice, and whether doth he ſupply his abſence by a Curate that is ſufficiently licenſed to preach in in that cure of his, whereon he himſelfe is not reſident: or otherwiſe, in caſe he doth not finde a Preaching miniſter there, by reaſon of the ſmal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe thereof, whether doth hee preach at both of his Benefices vſually himſelfe, according to the 47 canon?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Whether is your Curate licenced to ſerue by the Biſhop of this Dioceſſe, or by any other, and by whom? whether doth your miniſter or Curate ſerue more cures then one, contrary to the 48 canon: if yea, then what other Cure doth he alſo ſerue?</p>
               <p n="13">13 If your miniſter bee not licenced to preach as aforeſayd, whether
<pb facs="tcp:27114:3"/>
doth he read homilies, or rather take vpon him to expound the Scriptures either in his owne cure or elſewhere, contrary to the 49 canon. If yea, then you are to preſent him, &amp; ſpecifie the place where he hath ſo preached.</p>
               <p n="14">14 Whether hath any perſon beene admitted to preach within your church or chappell, but ſuch as you haue well knowen to be ſufficiently licenſed: whom haue you ſo admitted, you ſhall preſent their names, and how oft haue any ſuch béene admitted to preach, and by whoſe procure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; and whether haue you cauſed euery ſtrange Preacher, licenſed or not licenſed, to ſubſcribe his name, together with the day whe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> he preached, according to the 50 and 51 canons: and if he were licenced, then by whom he was licenſed: And whether haue they, or any other preached in your church, not being ſoberly &amp; decently apparelled, according to the 74 canon?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether doth your Lecturer and Preacher, reade diuine ſeruice, and adminiſter the Sacraments in his owne perſon, twice euery yéere, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeruing all the ceremonies in the Booke of common Prayer eſtabliſhed, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the 56 canon.</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether doth your Miniſter weare the Surplice whileſt hée is ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the publike prayers, and adminiſtring the Sacraments: and if he be any Graduate, whether then doth he alſo weare vpon his Surplice, during the times aforeſaid, ſuch a hood as by the order of his Vniuerſitie is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gréeable to his degrée, according to the 58 canon.</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether doth your Miniſter on euery Sunday and Holiday before Euening prayer, for halfe an houre or more, examine &amp; inſtruct the youth and ignorant perſons of his pariſh, in the ten Commandements, the Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles of Beléefe, &amp; the Lords Prayer, as alſo the Catechiſme, laſt ſet foorth in the Booke of Common Prayer, whereby the children of the Pariſh may be prepared for confirmation according to the 90 canon?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether hath your miniſter without licence from the Archbiſhop, the Biſhop of the Dioces, or his Chancellor, ſolemnized marriage betwixt any parties, the Banes not being three ſeuerall Sandayes or Holidayes, firſt publiſhed, in time of Diuine ſeruice, in the ſeuerall churches or chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pels of ſeuerall abode, according to the booke of Common prayer, and the 62 canon: and that alſo betwixt the houres of eight and twelue in the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noone, contrary vnto the 102 canon?</p>
               <p n="19">19 Whether hath your miniſter, ſince the laſt canons publiſhed, ſolem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nized any mariage betwixt any perſons, being vnder the age of 21 yéeres, although the Banes be thrice aſked, before ſuch time as the Parents haue made knowen vnto him their conſent therunto, contrary to the 99 and 100 canons: and whether hath he married any of another Dioceſſe: and who are they: and by what authority, and when?</p>
               <p n="20">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27114:4"/>20 Whether doth your Miniſter vpon Sundaies at morning praier, declare vnto the Pariſhioners, what Holidaies and faſting daies are ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to bée kept the wéeke following, according to the 64. Canon, wherby they may be put in minde to prepare themſelues accordingly, and to repaire to Church to publike praier, as by law they are bound.</p>
               <p n="21">21 Whether doth anie Miniſter in the Rogation daies, vſe the peram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bulation of the circuit of the Pariſh appointed by law, and in the ſame perambulation, mooue the people to giue thankes to God for his benefits, vſing ſuch Pſalmes, Praiers, Homilies, as are to that end ſet forth.</p>
               <p n="22">22 Whether doth anie man (being neither miniſter nor Deacon) read Common praier openly in your Church or Chappell, or adminiſter the Sacrament of Baptiſme, or ſolemnize matrimonie, or take vpon him to practize anie other miniſteriall dutie in the Church, that is preſcribed to be executed particularlie by ſuch, as are either miniſters, or Deacons: and what is his name that ſo doth.</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether doth your miniſter euerie ſix months denounce in his Pariſh, all ſuch of his Pariſh, as doe perſeuere in the ſentence of excom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication, not ſéeking to be abſolued: and whether hath hee admitted anie perſon excommunicate, into the Church, without a certificate of his abſolution from the Ordinarie or other competent Iudge, vnder his ſeale, according to the Canons.</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether doth your Miniſter, being a Preacher, endeauour &amp; labor diligently with mildnes and temperance to conferre with, &amp; thereby to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claime the popiſh recuſants in his Pariſh from their errors, if there be any ſuch there being: and whether is he painefull in viſiting the ſicke, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Booke of common prayer, &amp; the canons in that caſe prouided.</p>
               <p n="25">25 Whether is your Parſon, Vicar, Lecturer, or Curate, too much frequent, or ouer conuerſant with, or a fauourer of Recuſants, whereby he may be ſuſpected not to be ſincere in Religion.</p>
               <p n="26">26 Whether hath your miniſter, or anie other taken vpon him the place of a miniſter, preached, baptized children (vnleſſe in caſe of neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitie) ſolemnized marriage, churched anie woman, or miniſtred the holie communion in anie priuate houſe or houſes: If yea, then where: whom, and how often hath he ſo offended in anie of the Premiſes.</p>
               <p n="27">27 Whether hath your Miniſter taken vpon him to appoint anie pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like or priuate faſts, or propheſies not approoued and eſtabliſhed by law, or publike authoritie, or hath he attempted vpon anie pretence either of poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion, by faſting &amp; praier to caſt out diuels, contrarie vnto the 72. canon.</p>
               <p n="28">28 Whether hath your Miniſter, or anie other perſon or perſons with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in your Pariſh, vſed to méete in anie priuate houſe or other place, and to holde priuate conuenticles, contrarie to the 73. Canon; if yea, then you
<pb facs="tcp:27114:4"/>
ſhall preſent them all and euerie one of them.</p>
               <p n="29">29 Whether doth your Miniſter vſe ſuch decencie and comelineſſe in his apparell, as by the 74. Conſtitution is enioyned, as be all at home, as when he goeth abroad.</p>
               <p n="30">30 Whether doe you know in your pariſh, any that hauing heertofore taken vpon him or them the order of Preiſthood, or of a Deacon, hath ſince relinquiſhed the ſame, and betaken himſelfe in the courſe of his life, as a lay man, neglecting his vocation: if yea, then you ſhall preſent his name, and the place of his abode.</p>
               <p n="31">31 Whether is your Miniſter noted or defamed to haue obtained his benefice by ſymonie, or reputed to be an incontinent perſon, or doth kéepe anie man or woman in his houſe, that are ſuſpected either to bee of euill Religion or bad life; himſelfe to be a common drunkard, or to be a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon hunter of Tauernes, Ale houſes or other ſuſpected places; a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon gameſter, or player at dice, or other vnlawfull games; a common Swearer, or notorious perſon, or faulty in any other crime puniſhable by the Eccleſiaſticall cenſures, whereby he is offenſiue and ſcandalous to his function or miniſtery.</p>
               <p n="32">32 Whether doth your Miniſter vſe the forme of Thankeſgiuing to to women after childbirth: and whether hath he admitted any thereunto that was begotten with childe in adultery, or fornication, without licenſe of his Ordinary? And whether haue any married wiues refuſed to come to Church according to the Book of Common Praier, to giue God thanks after childbirth, if any bee faulty héerein, you ſhall preſent their names.</p>
               <p n="33">33 Whether doth your Miniſter baptize anie children in anie Baſon or other veſſell then in the ordinarie Font, being placed in the Church, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the 81. canon, or doth vſe to put anie Baſon into it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Articles concerning the Church.</head>
               <p>WHether haue you in your ſeuerall churches and chappels the booke of conſtitutions, or canons Eccleſiaſticall, ready to bée read by your miniſter, according to his Maieſties pleaſure, publiſhed by his High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe authoritie vnder the great ſeale of England.</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether is there in your church or chappell one parchment Regiſter Booke prouided for Chriſtnings, Mariages, and Burials: and whether is the ſame duely and exactly kept according to the Conſtitutions in that behalfe prouided? and a tranſcript thereof brought in yéerely, within one moneth after Eaſter, into my Lord Biſhops principall Regiſters Office? And whether doth your miniſter vpon euerie Sundaie read the names of all ſuch as haue béene married, chriſtned, or buried in the wéeke before.</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether haue you prouided a faire great Bible of the laſt Tranſla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,
<pb facs="tcp:27114:5"/>
the book of Common prayer, lately commanded by his Maieſties au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoritie onely to be vſed: and the Booke of Homilies, and two Pſalters: and whether haue you in your Church or Chappell a Font of ſtone ſet vp in the ancient vſuall place, a conuenient &amp; decent Communion Table, ſtanding vpon a frame, with a carpet of ſilke, or ſome other decent ſtuffe, and a faire Linnen cloth to lay thereon at the Communion time: and whether i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the ſame then placed in ſuch conuenient ſort within the Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cell or Church, as that the miniſter may be beſt heard in his prayer and Adminiſtration, and that the greater number may communicate: And whether are the Ten Commandements ſet vpon the Caſt end of your Church or Chappell, where the people may beſt ſée and reade them, and other ſentences of holy Scriptures written on the wals likewiſe, for the ſame purpoſe?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether haue you a conuenient ſeat for your Miniſter to read ſeruice in, together with a comely Pulpit ſet vp in a conuenient place, with a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent cloth or cuſhion for the ſame: a comely large Surplice, a faire Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion Cup of ſiluer, and a couer agréeable for the ſame, with all other things and ornaments neceſſary for the celebration of Diuine Seruice, and adminiſtration of the Sacraments; and a ſtrong cheſt for the Almes of the poore, with three locks and keyes, and another cheſt for the kéeping of the Ornaments of the church and Regiſter booke.</p>
               <p n="5">5 How many Bells are there at this preſent hanging in the Bell-frée of your Pariſh church? And how many haue there béene héeretofore? whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther any of your ſaid Bells haue béene taken downe and ſold, or made a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, and what other church goods are now wanting in your ſaid church?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether are your Churches or Chappels, with the chancels therof, &amp; your Parſonage, or Vicarage houſe, and all other houſing thereto belon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging, in good reparations, and decent and comely kept, as well within as without, the ſeats well maintained, your church yards well fenced, and kept without abuſe, according to the 85 canon: If not, then through whoſe default, and what defects are? All theſe things in theſe Articles, to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pared, according to the canons vnder the Title appertaining to churches.</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether haue you ſince the laſt <hi>Metropoliticall Viſitation</hi> of the moſt Reuerend Father, the now (Lord Arch biſhop of <hi>Canterbury</hi>) taken a true Terriar of all the Glebe land, Houſes, Tenements, Orchyards, Gardens, and portions of Tithes (whether within your Pariſh or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out) belonging to your Parſonage or Vicarage, and deliuered the ſame into the office of the Regiſter of this Dioceſſe?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:27114:5"/>
               <head>Articles concerning Schoole-maſters.</head>
               <p>WHether the Schoole-maſter or Schoole-maſters within your pariſh, openly or priuately, in any Noble or Gentlemans houſe, or in any other place, be of good and ſincere religion, life, and conuerſation, and be diligent in teaching and bringing vp of youth, and whether they haue béene examined, allowed, and licenced for Schoole-maſters, by the Ordinarie in that behalfe: and how many ſeuerall Schoole-maſters haue you, and what be their names?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether your Schoole-maſter or Schoole-maſters, do themſelues re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiue the holy Communion as often as they ought to doe: and whether do all your Schollers, which be of age ſufficient, and of capacity by inſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, to receiue the Lords Supper, come to the Communion, either in your Church, or where their Parents dwell, once euerie yeere, and bee diligent to heare common praier?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether the Schoolemaſter, or Schoolemaſters, either priuate or publike, doe teach their Schollers the Catechiſme authorized by publike Authoritie, at the leaſt once euerie weeke, and doe enſtruct and examine them in the ſame, and do teach any other catechiſme, and what catechiſme is it that they doe ſo teach?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether your Schoolemaſter or Schoolemaſters, or anie of them, be known or ſuſpected to read vnto their Schollers priuately, any vnlawfull books, or priuately to enſtruct them in their young yéeres, either in popery, ſuperſtition, or diſobedience, or contempt to his Maieſtie, and his Lawes Eccleſiaſticall by publique authoritie allowed?</p>
               <p n="5">5 What Recuſant Papiſts are there in your Pariſh: and whether doe they, or any of them kéep any Schoolmaſter in their houſe, which commeth not to Church, to heare Diuine Seruice, and receiue the Communion: what is his name: and how long hath he taught?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether the Schoolemaſter or Schoolemaſters within your Pariſh, doe teach his or their Schollers any other Grammar then that which is called the Kings Grammar; ſet foorth by the authoritie of King <hi>Henry</hi> the eight, teaching the preſcript forme thereof, whereby the Schollers may perfectly vnderſtand their Grammar rules and conſtructions.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Articles concerning Pariſhioners, and  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>hers of the Laytie.</head>
               <p>WHether is there any within your Pariſh, that hath or do<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pugne the Kings Maieſties Supremacie and authority in cauſes Eccleſiaſticall, or doe anie waie, or in anie part impeach the ſame, being reſtored to the Crowne by the Lawes of this Realme eſtabliſhed in that behalfe?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether is there anie in your Pariſh that denieth the Church of
<pb facs="tcp:27114:6"/>
England, by Law eſtabliſhed vnder the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie, to be a true and Apoſtolicall Church, teaching and maintaining the doctrine of the Apoſtles.</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether is there any in your Pariſh that doe impugne any of the Articles of Religion, agréed vpon in <hi>Anno</hi> 1562. and eſtabliſhed in the Church of England?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether is there any in your Pariſh, that doth impugne or ſpeake againſt the Rites and Ceremonies eſtabliſhed in the Church of England, or the lawfull vſe of them? you ſhall preſent their names.</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether are there any in your Pariſh that doe impugne the gouern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Church of England, vnder the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie, by Arch-biſhops, Biſhops, Archdeacons, &amp; the reſt that beare office in the ſame; affirming that y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame is Antichriſtia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, or repugna<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> word of God.</p>
               <p n="6">6 VVhether is there any in your Pariſh, that impugne the forme of conſecrating &amp; ordaining of Archbiſhops, Biſhops, Prieſts, or Deacons: affirming that the ſame is repugnant to the word of God, or that they, who are ſo ordered in that ſame forme, are not lawfully made.</p>
               <p n="7">7 VVhether is there any in your pariſh, that doth hold or frequent any conuenticles or priuate méetings, and there doe confer, to agree vpon anie priuate orders, other then ſuch as are by the canons ſet foorth by publique authoritie, to be by them, or any others in Church gouernment obſerued?</p>
               <p n="8">8 VVhether any perſons haue lurked or tippled in Tauernes or Ale-houſes on Sundayes or other Holidayes, or vſed his or their manuall craft or trade, to keepe their ſhops open vpon the ſaid dayes, or any of them, and eſpecially in the time of diuine Seruice.</p>
               <p n="9">9 VVhether are there any in your Pariſh that doe or haue prophaned (ſince his Maieſties laſt generall pardon) the Lords day, called Sunday, or other Holidaies, contrarie to the orders of the Church of England pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed in that behalfe.</p>
               <p n="10">10 VVhether hath any perſon in your pariſh quarrelled, ſtricken, or vſed any violence vnto, or with your Miniſter, or any other in the Church, or Church-yard, or vſed himſelfe diſorderly in the Church by filthy and prophane talke, or any other rude and immodeſt behauiour.</p>
               <p n="11">11 VVhether is that due reuerence &amp; humble ſubmiſſion vſed in your Church or Chappell in the time of diuine Seruice, as by the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>8 Conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is preſcribed: and whether each one in the Church or Chappell do ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply &amp; order himſelfe there, in time of diuine Seruice, as by the latter part of the ſame Conſtitution is commendably enioyned?</p>
               <p n="12">12 VVhether the Church-wardens and Queſtmen, from time to time, doe their diligence in not ſuffering any idleperſons or Loiterers to abide
<pb facs="tcp:27114:6"/>
either in the Church-yard or Church-porch in Seruice or Sermon time, but cauſing them either to come into Church to heare Diuine Seruice, or to depart, and not to diſturbe ſuch as are hearers there.</p>
               <p n="13">13 VVhether the Church-wardens doe prouide againſt euery commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion with the aduice of the miniſter, a ſufficient quantitie of fine white bread, and of good and wholeſome wine for the number of the Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cants that ſhall receiue, and that to be brought in a cleane and ſweet ſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding pot of Pewter, or other pure metall?</p>
               <p n="14">14 VVhether haue anie in your Pariſh béene Godfathers or Godmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers to their owne children? or whether your Miniſter, or anie Godfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers or Godmothers haue vſed, or doe vſe anie other forme, anſwer, or ſpéech in Baptiſme, then is in the booke of common prayer appointed? Or whether anie which haue not communicated, bee admitted to bee Godmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, contrary to the 29 canon.</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether is there any in your Pariſh that doe refuſe to haue their children baptized, or themſelues to receiue the communion at the hands of your Miniſter, becauſe he is no Preacher? you ſhall preſent their names. And if your Miniſter, ſithence the publiſhing of the ſayd Booke of Canons, haue receiued any ſuch perſons (being not of his owne cure) to the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, or baptized any of their children, you ſhall likewiſe preſent him.</p>
               <p n="16">16 VVhether doe all Fathers, Mothers, Maſters, and Miſtreſſes, cauſe their children, ſeruants, and apprentiſes, to come to the catechiſme vpon the Sundaies and Holy-daies before Euening praier, to heare, and to bee enſtructed and taught therein: and thoſe that doe not their duties heerein, you ſhall preſent their names.</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether haue you or your predeceſſors Churchwardens there ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered ſince the laſt pardon, any plaies, banquets, feaſts, church-ales, drin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kings, or any other prophane vſages, to be kept in your church, chappell, or church-yards, or bels to be rung ſuperſtitiouſly vpon Holidayes, or eues, abrogated by the booke of common praier, contrary to the 68 canon.</p>
               <p n="18">18 How many inhabitants within your pariſh, men or women, aboue the age of xvi. yéeres, doe refuſe to frequent diuine Seruice eſtabliſhed by publike authority of this Realme, or to receiue the holy Communion, or are negligent therein: what be their names, and of what degrée, ſtate or trade of life are they? you are to preſent them all of both ſorts.</p>
               <p n="19">19 Whether doe any of the inhabitants of your ſaid pariſh entertaine within their houſe any ſoiourners, lodgers, or any common reſorters and gueſts, who refuſe to frequent diuine Seruice, or receiue the holy Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, as aforeſayd, what be their names, of what quality or condition are they?</p>
               <p n="20">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27114:7"/>20 Whether are any of the ſayd popiſh Recuſants of inſolent behaui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our not without publike offence, or doe boldly buſie themſelues in ſedu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing and withdrawing others, either abroad or in their owne families, by enſtructing their children in popiſh religion, or by refuſing to entertaine any, eſpecially in place of greateſt ſeruice or truſt, but ſuch as concurre with them in opinion of Relgion, and what be their names that ſo doe?</p>
               <p n="21">21 How long the ſaid Popiſh Recuſants haue obſtinately abſtained ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther from diuine Seruice, or from the Communion, as is aforeſayd: whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of any long time, or onely ſince his Maieſties raigne, and how long?</p>
               <p n="22">22 What perſons aforeſaid within your Pariſh, either for the offence aforeſayd, or for any other contumacie or crime, doe remaine excommuni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated, what be their names, and for what cauſe, and how long haue they ſtood excommunicate?</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether were you the Church-wardens &amp; Queſt men choſen by the conſent of the Miniſter and Pariſhioners in Eaſter wéeke, according vnto the 89 and 90 Canons, and whether haue the Churchwardens before you, giuen vp a iuſt account for their time, and deliuered to you their ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors whatſoeuer money, or other things of right belonging to the Church, that was in their hands: according to the 89 canon?</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether doe all perſons aboue the age of ſixtéene yéeres, vſually reſort to heare diuine Seruice vpon Sundayes and Holidayes approued, and whether hath each one of your Pariſhioners (being aboue the age of ſixtéene yéeres, as aforeſaid) receiued the holy Communion thrice this laſt yéere, chiefly once at Eaſter in your pariſh Church knéeling? if no, then you ſhall preſent their names which haue not ſo done.</p>
               <p n="25">25 Whether haue you a fit pariſh Clark, aged twenty yéeres at leaſt, of honeſt conuerſation, and ſufficient for reading and writing, and whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther hee bee payd his wages without fraud, according to the moſt ancient cuſtome of your pariſh; if not then by whom is he ſo defrauded and denied, and whether he be choſen by the Parſon, or Vicar, or by whom, according to the 91 canon? is the Pariſh Clarke approued by the Ordinary, and doth he kéep the church cleane, and the doores lockt, is he diligent and ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uiceable to the miniſter?</p>
               <p n="26">26 Whether haue any in your pariſh béene married within the prohi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bited degrées, forbidden by the Law, and expreſſed in a certaine Table, publiſhed by authoritie in the yéere 1563. if yea, then you ſhall preſent their names: and whether haue you the ſayd Table publikely ſet in your Church, and faſtned to ſome conuenient place there?</p>
               <p n="27">27 Whether doth any heeretofore diuorced, kéepe company with any
<pb facs="tcp:27114:7"/>
other at bed and at boord, as man and wife, what bée their names, when and where they were married, and how long they ſo continued?</p>
               <p n="29">29 Whether haue you any in your Pariſh to your knowledge, or by common fame and report, which haue committed adulterie, fornication, or inceſt, or any Bawds, harborers, or receiuers of ſuch perſons, or publike<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly ſuſpected thereof, which haue not béene publikely puniſhed to your knowledge: if yea, then with whom: And whether are there any which are by common fame &amp; report reputed &amp; taken to bee common drunkards, blaſphemers of Gods moſt holy name, common &amp; vſuall ſwearers, filthy ſpeakers, raylers, ſowers of diſcord among their neighbours; or ſpea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers againſt Miniſters marriages, Vſurers, contrary to the ſtatute made in the 37. yéere of <hi>Henry</hi> the eight, Symoniacall perſons, fighters, braw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers, or quarreliers in Church or Church yard? you ſhall not faile to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent their names.</p>
               <p n="29">29 Whether haue any in your pariſh receiued or harboured any wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man begotten with childe out of wedlocke, and ſuffered them againe to depart without penance firſt enflicted vpon them by the Ordinary: You ſhall truly preſent as well the party harbouring, as harboured, and who is ſuſpected to haue committed Incontinency with her.</p>
               <p n="30">30 Whether any perſon or perſons ſuſpected or detected héeretofore of incontinency, and therefore departing out of your Pariſh for a ſeaſon, is now returned againe, or in what place elſe is hée or ſhee now abiding to your knowledge, or as you haue heard: you ſhall not faile to preſent the whole truth in that behalfe.</p>
               <p n="31">31 Whether ther be any perſon or perſons, Eccleſiaſticall or Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porall, within your Pariſh or elſewhere within this Dioceſſe, that haue retained or kept in their cuſtodie, or that read, ſell, vtter diſperſe, carrie or deliuer to others, any Engliſh bookes or libells, ſet foorth either on this ſide, or beyond the Seas, by Papiſts or Sectaries, againſt the Kings ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>premacie, in cauſes Eccleſiaſticall, or againſt true Religion and Catho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like doctrine now publikely profeſſed in this Church, or the Gouernment or Diſcipline of the Church of England, now within this Realme recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued and eſtabliſhed by common Authority, and what their Names and Syrnames are?</p>
               <p n="32">32 Whether there be any in your Pariſh, who are noted, knowne, or ſuſpected to conceale, or kéepe hidden in their houſes any Maſſe-bookes, Porteſſes, Breuiaries or other bookes of Popery or ſuperſtition, or anie Chalices, Copes, Veſtments, Albes, or other Ornaments of ſuperſtiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, vncancelled or vndefaced, which is to bee coniectured, they doe kéepe for a day; as they call it?</p>
               <p n="33">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27114:8"/>33 Whether any of your Pariſhioners, hauing a Preacher to their Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, or doe abſent themſelues from his Sermons, and reſort to any other place to heare other Preachers.</p>
               <p n="34">34 Whether there be any Inkéepers, Ale-wiues Victuallers, or Tip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers, that ſuffer or doe admit any perſon or perſons in their Houſes, to Eate, Drinke, or play at Dice, Cards, Tables, Bowles, or ſuch like Games, in the time of common Prayer, or Sermon, on Sundaies or Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lydaies; or any Butchers or others that commonly vſe to ſell meate, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther things in the time of common prayer, preaching, or reading of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies? And whether in any Faires or common markets falling vpon Sundaies, there be ſhewing of any wares before morning praier be done? And whether any Markets and ſelling of wares, be vſed or ſuffered in any Church yards, on the Saboth day, by common Packe men and Pedlers, going about, or any Butchers?</p>
               <p n="35">35 Whether hath your Miniſter or any of your Pariſh, without the conſent or priuity of the Ordinary, cauſed any to doe penance, or be puni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed, either openly or otherwiſe, for any crime, puniſhable by Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call Lawes onely: and what bée the Names of the parties that haue béene ſo puniſhed, and in what manner?</p>
               <p n="36">36 Whether there be any in your Pariſh, who will come to heare the Sermon, but will not come to the publike prayer, appointed by the book of common prayer, making a Schiſme or diuiſion (as it were) between the vſe of publike Prayer and Preaching. And whether there be any who be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing preſent at publike prayer, doe not deuoutly and humbly knéele vpon their knées at ſuch times as by the booke of common prayer they are ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed; to wit, when they make a generall confeſſion of their ſins: when all Prayers and Collects are read? and at the receiuing of the Holy Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, &amp;c. And what are their Names, that haue at any time ſhewed themſelues vndutifull and vnreuerend in that behalfe.</p>
               <p n="37">37 Whether there bee any married women or others within your pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, which after child birth, refuſe or contemne to come to the Church, to giue God thanks for their ſafe deliuery, and to haue their praiers publike<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly appointed in that behalfe, by the booke of Common Prayer.</p>
               <p n="38">38 Whether any within your Pariſh, doe reſort into Barnes, Fields, Woods, priuate houſes, or to any extraordinary expoſition of Scriptures, or conferences together: or that be drawers, or perſwaders of others, to any ſuch ſchiſmaticall conuenticle.</p>
               <p n="39">39 Whether any doe kéepe their children vnbaptized longer then is conuenient: vnleſſe that it be for ſickneſſe of the childe, or other vrgent occaſion? And whether any doe carry their children from the Pariſh they
<pb facs="tcp:27114:8"/>
are borne in, to other pariſhes to be baptized, and ſo refuſe their owne pariſh: or doe bring ſtrange Miniſters into their owne houſes, to baptize their children priuately, according to their owne Fantaſies?</p>
               <p n="40">40 Whether you haue knowne or heard any Fidlers or Minſtrels, or any other perſons, which goe vnder the name of Muſitians and Waytes, which either at Weddings, Churchings, or any other Feaſts, or méetings, haue ſung, or vſe to ſing any Songs, Ballads, or Rimes, tending to the diſgrace of Religion, or the Miniſters thereof: or tending to Profanenes, or the corruption of good manners? You ſhall truely preſent the names of ſuch, if you know them, or can learne them: As alſo the names of the Houſholder, or Houſholders, in whoſe houſe or houſes they haue ſung ſuch ſongs, as alſo the particular names of them before whom they haue ſung them.</p>
               <p n="41">41 VVhether doe the Church-wardens of your pariſh, looke diligently to the mending of the Church wayes: and whether the ſaid waies bee at the time of the yéere ſo ſufficiently mended, that the Pariſhioners may conueniently come to Church, from all places of the pariſh in winter time.</p>
               <p n="42">42 Whether doe you know of any other matter, of Eccleſiaſticall cog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance, worthy the preſentment in your Iudgement, aboue not expreſſed, which you hold fit to be reformed. And if you doe, you ſhall likewiſe pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent the ſame, by vertue of your Oathes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>AT the deliuery of your bill of <hi>Preſentment,</hi> you are likewiſe in the ſayd bill to ſet downe the names of all ſuch as haue beene buried at any time, ſince the laſt <hi>Viſitation,</hi> being Men, Mayds, or Widowes. And likewiſe the Miniſter, Church-wardens, and Side-men of euery pariſh, muſt in the ſayd bill of <hi>Preſentment,</hi> ſet downe beſides their preſenting, which they make of all <hi>Recuſants</hi> and <hi>Non-communicants,</hi> this Note following.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Recuſants Men</hi>—</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Recuſants Women</hi>—</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Non-communicants of both Sex</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Communicants of both Sex — in the whole Pariſh.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <p>So ſet downe the number of euery one, The <hi>Miniſter, Church-wardens,</hi> and <hi>Side-men,</hi> muſt put their hands to this note. And the olde <hi>Church-wardens</hi> are to be choſen <hi>Side-men.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
